{
    "id": "df7a0e9f7f86438e939681256397f687",
    "title": "Direct And Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "'She is my best friend,' he said. He said that she ............................. his best friend.",
            "description": "Simple present tense in the direct speech becomes simple past tense in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'She is waiting for us,' he said. /He said that she ............................... for them.",
            "description": "Present continuous in the direct speech becomes past continuous in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "was waiting",
                "has been waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'I have visited all the continents,' he said. / He said that he ............................. all the continents.",
            "description": "Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect tense in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "has visited",
                "had visited"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "'She has been living alone for years,' he said. / He said that she ............................... alone for years.",
            "description": "Present perfect continuous in the direct speech becomes past perfect continuous in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "was living",
                "has been living",
                "had been living"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "'She will help us,' he said. / He said that she .............................. help them.",
            "description": "Will becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'I want to go,' he said. He said that he .................................. to go.",
            "description": "Simple present tense in the direct speech becomes simple past tense in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "wants",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'I don't want to go,' she said. / She said that she .............................. to go.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't want",
                "doesn't want",
                "don't want"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "'I have watched that movie,' he said. / He said that he .................................... that movie.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have watched",
                "had watched",
                "has watched"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'She must leave now,' he said. / He said that she ............................... leave then.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "must",
                "had to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can't help you,' he said. / He said that he ................................. help me.",
            "description": "Can becomes could.",
            "answers": [
                "can't",
                "couldn't",
                "wouldn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'They will have gone,' he said. / He said that they .................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will have gone",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "'I am busy,' he shouted. / He shouted that he ...................................... busy.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}